If you don't hear me this time please tell me.
如果听不见我说话 请告诉我
I am sorry for being late,
抱歉我这次演讲
for this lecture
迟到了
but,
不过
Dr. Warren had time to explain to you,
沃伦医生会有时间向你们解释
about this experience.
这次的经历
Sometimes it is easier to understand
有时通过一个已经
this from a person,
达到某种境界的人
who has achieved it,
更容易了解一件事
than to understand from a person
比通过一个
who is talking from some tenth storey.
他在第十个层次说
That's what my father told me,
那就是为什么我父亲告诉我
that if somebody's born on the tenth storey,
如果某人在第十个层次出生
and the rest of them are on the first floor,
并且其他人都在第一个层次
if you start telling them from there they will first of all not listen,
如果你从第十个层次告诉他们 他们首先不听
nor will they understand what you see.
他们也不能理解你所见到的
It's not proper,
这是不正确的
that we should try to tell them something from a level,
我们应该试图在一个层次告诉他们一些事情
to a level, which is still there static,
很深的程度 那些还只是静态知识
in their mind.
在他们的头脑中
So one has to, raise their, consciousness,
因此他们必须要提高他们的意识
two three storeys so they start seeing that there's something beyond.
二三层因此他们开始看到有些东西超越了它
But, in doing so,
但是 在这种情况下
so many mistakes,
许多的错误
have been, there, before,
在那儿或者之前发生了
and some people have done it deliberately,
许多人故意的那样做
some are misguided
许多是被误导的
and some are doing it deliberately.
许多是故意的
Net result is just the same.
最终结果是一样的
Even if you give poison to someone by mistake,
即使你无意的给某人下毒
or in a misguided way, the result is the same.
或者是在被误导的情况下做的 结果是相同的
In the same way,
同样地
whether you are misguided,
不管你是被误导
or whether you do it deliberately, whatever is wrong
还是故意的 无论做错了什么
has an effect on the kundalini.
都会对昆达里尼有影响
Now the Aquarian Age,
现在这个宝瓶座的时代
is the word I picked up from Dr. Warren,
这个词是我从沃夫医生那个拿来
which is so true today.
今天它是如此的真实
Aquarian means the water carrier,
宝瓶座生的人意味着水的载体
and in Sanskrit language it is called as kumbha.
在梵文中它被称为kumbha
Kumbha is the one what we call the kundalini,
Kumbha就是我们所说的昆达利尼
the mooladhara is the kumbha,
根轮就是kumbha
where the kundalini is there, the power of kundalini is there.
昆达利尼位于那儿 昆达利尼的力量位于那儿
So to call it an Aquarian age must be some,
所以称之为宝瓶座时代
work of some, realized soul who could see that,
必须是有一些工作 已得自觉的灵可以看到
in this age the kundalini is going to be awakened,
在这个时代昆达利尼将要被唤醒
and that, an age will start of people getting their kundalini awakened.
这个时代将从一些人的昆达利尼被唤醒开始
Now I have already talked to you the other day about
我之前曾跟你们讲过
this second center, which is called as swadhisthana,
第二个能量中心 它被称为腹轮
which gives us our sustenance
是它给我们提供滋养
and also our power to create.
同时也提供我们创造的力量
The sustenance is created inside,
这种滋养在内在被创造出来
that green part, which is,
那个绿色的部分
represented by main ten Primordial Masters,
它由十大原始宗师所代表
and these ten Primordial Masters had another
这十大原始宗师有另外一系列
series of masters who were called as,
我们称之为
Disciple Principles.
门徒原则
Now about these people I have talked to you last time,
关于这些大师 我上次曾经跟你们说过
but today I would like to speak to you
但是今天我想讲一下
about other centers, specially this nabhi,
其他的能量中心 尤其是脐轮
which is the navel centre which is very important in human beings.
它位于人类肚脐眼的中心 是一个对人类而言非常重要的轮穴
This is the centre by which we seek.
我们是通过这个能量中心开始追寻
When in amoeba stage we seek,
在阿米巴虫阶段 我们追求
food, at a higher level
食物 在稍高的层面
we start seeking heights,
我们开始追求身材高大
like when they became mammoth and all these
比如说当他们进化成为猛犸象 所有
animals they wanted to have a height,
的动物 它们希望身材高大
to go over the trees to be able to master them and to eat the leaves,
好走在丛林之中 能够够得着树并吃到树上的叶子
but they became so much outsized with their height,
但是那样的身高让他们太过高大
that they had to become smaller animals,
他们不得不变成更小一些的动物
like say intelligent animals,
比如说智能动物
and, like say cats and things like that, cat family.
像猫以及猫科动物之类的
And this is how the evolution has been,
这就是进化是如何发生的
brought forth through our seeking as amoeba,
从我们是从阿米巴虫就开始追寻
then as animals and now as human beings.
然后是作为动物去追寻 现在是作为人类去追寻
As we have evolved higher and higher,
当我们进化得越来越高级的时候
we have become subtler and subtler in our seeking.
我们的追求也越来越精微
For example the people who are seeking say power,
举个例子 有些人追求权力
are not so evolved as people who are seeking their spirit, no doubt about it.
这些人就没有那些追求灵性的人进化 毫无疑问
Because you have gone through that, you have had enough of it.
因为你已经经历过了追求权力的阶段 你已经受够了对权力的追求
Maybe last lives you might have been kings and queens
也许过去几世中你是国王或皇后
and you must have seen all the jokes of it,
你一定是看尽了权力的可笑之处
so you said now, it's had enough of it,
所以你觉得 已经够了
this power business, we don't want to have anymore,
有关权力的事情 我们不想再有了
such a headache we don't want to have.
我们不想再有这些头痛的事
The people who are seeking money also,
追求金钱的人也是
are the people who have had enough of it
他们觉得已经够了
and they were fed up of it so they said now we have had it.
他们厌烦了 他们说我们已经有了
So now you are seekers of, something beyond.
所以现在你们在追寻更高的东西
It has been always so, something beyond we seek,
向来都是这样 有更高的追求
but this seeking beyond is not described
但是超越这个追求却并没有被描述给如此众多的人
to so many people and they are not able to understand
他们也不能够理解什么是超越
what is the beyond, that's why this center is very important,
这就是为什么这个轮穴
of your evolutionary process.
在你们的进化过程中是如此重要
Now, first of all as I have told you that we have to be in balance,
首先 正如我已经告诉过你们的 我们必须处于平衡之中
that's one thing we must have is the balance in life.
在生活中有一件事我们必须要做到 那就是在平衡之中
I mean in commonsense also we can see supposing there's
我的意思是说 根据常识 我们可以假设这有一辆车
a car going only on one wheel,
它行驶在一只轮子上
how many would like to travel by that.
有多少人会想乘坐这样的车
Anything that you do in life has to have a balance,
你在生活中做的任何事情都需要有平衡
otherwise, anything, even catching something, holding something
否则的话 任何事情 即使只是抓着东西 拿着东西
or, small small things, even riding a bicycle
或者更小的事情 如骑自行车
you know that you have to have a balance.
你知道你都必须保持平衡
So if the kundalini has to move,
所以如果昆达利尼要上升
you have to be a balanced personality,
你必须要有一个平衡的人格
a personality with a temperate,
温和的人格
nature and must have a balanced attitude towards life.
自然的 平衡的态度对待生活
That is very important, but in case it is not,
这是非常重要的 但是万一你不是这样
you can be sucked into the central path of the sushumna,
你可以被吸入到中脉的中心路径
in the central path of your evolution.
中脉是在你们进化的中心路径
Now the evolution takes place by remaining in the central path.
现在通过保持在中间的通道 进化发生了
Those who go to the extremes fall out of this.
那些走向极端的人被淘汰
Now the virus that we suffer from very commonly,
那些通常让我们受苦的病毒
is nothing but a kind of a vegetable
就像植物
which is fallen out of evolution.
在进化中被淘汰的植物
Now the vegetable that we call as tobacco,
现在我们称之为烟草的植物N
is going to fall out of complete evolution and you'll be surprised after
将在完全的进化中出局 你会感到惊讶
some years you will not find
多年后你找不到
any tobacco growing anywhere because it will go out of evolution,
任何地方在种烟草 因为它将被进化过程淘汰
thanks to human beings that they misunderstood the role of tobacco.
都是因为人类误解了烟草的用途
Tobacco is an insecticide, is to be used
烟草是一种杀虫剂 是用来
for killing the insects and not to kill yourself.
杀灭害虫而不是自杀
But, we sometimes forget, that whatever,
但是我们有时忘记了
God has created for the good,
神所创造的一切是为了我们的好处
sometimes we can use it for our destruction.
有时候我们用它来自我毁灭
Same is alcohol. Alcohol was created for polishing,
酒精也是一样 创造出酒精是用来抛光的
it's very good for example if you have to polish your crystal,
比如你需要擦亮水晶 它很好用
you should use gin is very good,
你应该用杜松子酒 很有效
for diamonds or anything.
用于钻石或其它东西
Is just a polish, it's a polish for the,
只是一种清洁剂 它是为了擦东西
for anything, it gives a polish. You see alcohol is a polish and
它提供擦亮清洁的作用 酒精就是清洁剂
its composition is such that it gives a polish to a thing.
它的合成物就是使一个东西干净
Now God wanted you to have polished surfaces and polished things
上天想让你拥有擦得亮亮的表面和东西
and all the clean look of it so He gave you this polish.
很干净的样子 所以他给你清洁剂
Now you started drinking it, now what to do.
现在你们开始喝它 该怎么办
He never asked you to drink, but if you drink that,
他从来没有要求你喝 如果你喝酒
then it polishes your intestines also.
它也擦干净你的内脏
But it has its own nature. It doesn't have any
它有自己的本性 它没有
idea of morality, poor thing what, we can't blame the alcohol,
任何道德的概念 我们不能责怪酒精
because it is suppose to polish, wherever you put it it polishes all right,
因为酒精是用来清洁的 无论你把它放在哪里 它都会自动清洁
so it polishes your liver also nicely.
因此 它也会很好地清洁你的肝脏
And when the liver is nicely polished then what happens
当肝脏自身被很好地清洁了后 接下来会发生什么
that the heat from the liver,
来自于肝脏的热量
which is for the expulsion from the body,
本来是要排出体外的
it has to pass into the bloodstream, cannot because there's a,
却不得不流入到血流中 不能被排出的原因是因为会遇到
barrier and because of that barrier
阻碍 就是因为这种阻碍
poor liver does not know what to do.
可怜的肝脏不知如何是好
It just goes on accumulating all the heat within it
它只在其内部持续地增加所有的热量
and that's how your liver goes out of circulation of anything,
这也就是为什么你的肝脏不能再过滤任何东西的原因
and you have liver problems and you feel very giddy, nauseated,
你因此会得肝病 并感到头晕恶心
and liver is the one which really cleanses your attention.
肝脏能净化你的注意力
Whatever you gather from your attention it cleanses.
无论你的注意力收集什么它都净化
So you become horrid I mean you are all the time angry,
所以当你经常生气时会变得极不友好
hot-tempered, you bark at people all the time,
hot-tempered, you bark at people all the time, 脾气暴躁 你经常对人咆哮
all that thing is typically liverish you see. We grow tall,
所有这些都是典型的肝病征兆 我们变得自大
like that absolutely straight line, and
像绝对的直线
you become very hot-tempered. Sometimes you could be hawk-like you know,
你变得很暴躁 有时候你可能会像鹰一样
people will be afraid of going nearer such a person,
人们害怕去接近这样的人
because such a person can be very dry personality
因此这样的人性格孤僻
and that's why you'll find,
这就是为什么你会发现
drunkard people if you they're over-drunk you go near them they'll just
如果你去接近那些喝得过多的酒鬼他们会
beat you for nothing at all. I mean
没来由的揍你 我的意思是
it sometimes happens that by chance
这样的事偶然发生
if you go and ask some drunkard that: 'What's the time?' in the night
如果你去问问一些酒鬼 现在几点 是晚上
you will have it.
你会得到这样的答案
So, because it spoils your awareness
因此 喝酒会破坏你的意识
and in that awareness a nice man also could be like that,
即使是个好人也会变得这样
but of course there could be a case where a person might become better.
当然也有一种情况会使这个人感觉很好
That is also another thing that can happen
这是另一种可能发生的情况
when you get possessed by this
当你所拥有
left-side movement because alcohol reduces
能量向左侧移动因为酒精的减少
your awareness and you go to the left-side movement to the left side,
你自觉到能量从左移到右边（是右边吗）
may give you, a feeling 'Oh I'm very much better now'
这可能给你一种感觉　我现在好多了
and sort of you get happy because your ego is subsided and everything is
然后你就变得开心因为你的自我是平静的　并且感觉所有的事情
alright and 'I'm really moderate now, I cannot hit anyone
都很美好　我现在真的变得温和了　我不能打任何人
and let me have little bit and sleep off'.
让我有一点好的睡眠
But next day there's a hangover
但是第二天会有一点后遗症
and you feel so horrible with it,
你会感觉很可怕
that you don't know what to do, I mean
使你不知道怎么办　我是说
it's something, then again you want to have it in the night
这个东西　是使你在晚上时再次想拥有的东西
because you want to again go to the same realm into the left side.
因为你又想进入左边的相同领域
Now this left side realm, apparently shows that there is
现在这左边的领域　明显地表露出
reduction in the weight of the ego, but it does not, it wobbles.
自我的份量减少了　但是它其实没有　它是不稳定的
What happens that you go to the superego on the left hand side you see there,
其实是你们进入了超我　你看你的左手
and the ego then thinks that it has gone down because the superego
然后自我以为它消失了因为超我
increases in size. But when superego increases, the ego is pushed down
的规模在增加　但是超我增强了　自我就被推倒了
and then when you come to your ego condition,
然后当你来到自我层面时
then it pushes down so there's a big wobbling going on,
它处于失落中所以就开始摇摆不定
and such people get ultimately very much confused.
像这样的人最后就变得非常困惑
They might end up in a lunatic asylum I don't know what they do,
他们可能最终进入一精神病院　我不知道他们做了什么
but, when they are even sane you can find they lose the grip over life,
但是当他们神智清醒的时候 你会发现他们失去了对生活的控制
for example such people can become very frivolous, and
比如他们变得非常无聊
cannot feel the joy of life without drinking.
没有了酒精 无法感受到生活的快乐
It's most amazing that people can't enjoy each other unless and until
最让人吃惊是人们不能享受彼此
there's a glass in between. I mean human beings are so beautiful,
除非在他们之间有玻璃相隔 人类是如此漂亮
and they have the capacity to enjoy each other, so much,
他们有享受彼此的能力
they are the only ones who are blessed more than anybody else.
相比其他生物，他们是唯一享受到更多祝福的
But if there's a glass all the time in between
如果人们用玻璃相隔
then they can just bark at each other,
他们只能朝对方咆哮
they cannot enjoy each other.
而不能享受彼此
The enjoyment should be complete when there's nothing in between.
应该彻底的享受当没有任何东西在其中
Now this is what I was telling you, this nahbi chakra.
现在这就是我要告诉你的 脐轮
This nahbi chakra gets, ruined also when we take to,
这个脐轮获取 它也会遭到破坏当我们摄取
alcohols or serious things like that, drugs and,
酒精或者其他不好的东西像毒品和
even I've seen certain medicines can spoil this.
甚至一些日常我看到的药物也能破坏它
Then you get a problem with the other things like digestion,
然后你会在其他事情上出问题像是消化作用
you get constipation, all sorts of things take place,
你会便秘 各种各样的事情会发生
by which you develop
你会有
gas troubles and other troubles and then your heart troubles and it
气体的问题和其他问题然后你的心脏也会出问题
goes on one after another.
问题会一个接着一个
I do not say that it's only alcohol that will cause.
我不是说这个只有酒精会引起
There are other causes also, but alcohol can never be helpful,
这也会有其他的原因 但是酒精绝不会有帮助
in giving you good health. Some people
在给予你一个好的健康方面 许多人
have a feeling that if you take alcohol then only you will keep good health.
有个感觉是果然你饮用了酒精就只有你会保持健康的身体
Is a wrong thing. Because health is not only physical health.
这是个错误的事情 因为健康不只是身体上的健康
It's also mental health. People think that
它也意味着精神的健康 人们认为
physical health is the end of everything,
身体上的健康是任何事情的终结
is absolutely wrong because we are not only the physical being.
这是完全错误的因为我们不只是形体的存在
We are also the mental being and the emotional being.
我们也是精神的存在和情感的存在
And when you play too much with your nahbi chakra
当你脐轮消耗得太多
you have the biggest problem and that is that
你有最大的问题就是
you can never be successful in life
你不能在生活
as far as enjoyment is concerned, of your achievements.
享受你的成就言
For example a person becomes rich,
比如一个人变得富有
unduly rich he becomes, is a blessing
他变得极其富有 这是祝福
I should say of nahbi chakra on the right-hand side.
我应该谈一谈右脐轮.
Right-hand side nahbi chakra can give you a lot of wealth,
右脐轮给你大量的财富
a lot of money and you'll have ten cars and fifteen people attending to you,
许多钱 你将拥有十辆车 有十五个人照料你
everything you may have but, it cannot,
你拥有所有东西 但是
it cannot give you the satisfaction of life.
它无法使你对生活感到满足
You will go on accumulating and end up with a suicide or something like that
你将继续追求金钱最后以自杀之类的行为告终
and you would not know why you are
而你不会知道自己为何
bent upon committing suicide.
想要自杀
That's why in all affluent countries you find
那就是为什么在所有发达国家你会发现
people are planning to commit suicide
人们正打算自杀
and the more affluent they are the worse it is.
而且越是富有人们越是糟糕
But the left side gets completely dried.
而同时脐轮左边变得完全干枯
Now the left side is the centre of
脐轮左边代表
the family life, the Gruhalaxshmi,
家庭生活 它的神祇是古哈拉克什米
the Goddess of the family,
即掌管家庭的女神
the household you see.
是管理家务的
A person who runs after money too much,
如果一个人过分追求金钱
forgets his family. He has no time for his family.
他就会忽略家庭 他没有时间关心他的家庭
The husband and wife may meet somewhere
丈夫和妻子也许
on the airport
在机场某个地方见面
or may just wave at each other sometimes you see, crossing each other,
或者只是相互挥个手 然后擦肩而过？？
or the children suffer the most.
孩子遭受得最多？？
And in that case the women also then take up with the men,
如此一来女人不久也会找外遇
they compete what's wrong, they start copying men,
她们完全错误 她们开始模仿男性
and in so doing so,
像男人那样做？？
when they compete with each other,
当他们互相比较时
then what happens, that this family life gets disturbed.
然后会发生什么呢　这个家庭就乱了
The woman of the household is dissatisfied,
这个家庭主妇感觉到不满意
her ego is not satisfied. In olden times
她的自我不满意　在古时候
the man used to go in the jungle,
丈夫通常都是去丛林
and get all the wood cut, bring it home,
砍柴带回家
and give it to the wife and wife used to cook.
然后把它给妻子用来做饭用
There was no problem because there was barter system.
这样做是有道理的因为有物物交换制度
He could see her working in the household.
他可以看她在家工作
Now the husband earns the money
现在丈夫挣了钱
and the woman spends. I mean that also requires some work,
并且女人花钱消费 我的意思是还需要做一些工作
isn't it to spend the money.
而不是花钱
But to man it looks like, that I'm the earning member and she's the spender.
但对于男人说就象 我是挣钱的而她是花钱的
So she said all right, I will also earn. But in this too much of competition,
所以她说好吧 我也去挣钱 但是在这样的情况下有太多的竞争
too much of competition like this, between the two,
太多的竞争象现在这样 在两者之间
what happens, the family suffers, the children suffer
会发生什么事 家庭受苦 孩子受罪
and such a person will have problem with the wife, the wife will have
并且这样的人会与妻子有问题 妻子也会
problem with the husband and you can always feel that center on this finger,
与丈夫有问题并且你也在这个手指上感受到那个中心
if that finger is catching, that means there's something wrong
如果那个手指有阻塞 意味着有些问题
with your family relationship,
在你的家庭关系中
that you have to adjust yourself, or he has to adjust.
你必须调整你自己 或者他必须调整
It's an important thing. Because you are like the flowers
这是一个重要的事 因为你们就象花朵
which have to produce a fruit.
必须产生果实
That's what nature wants.
那是大自然所希望的
Nature wants that you are there to produce the,
大自然希望你们结出
fruit, that is your children.
果实 那就是你的孩子
That's why you are men and women. That's the basics.
那就是为什么你们是男人和女人 这是根本
Now, if you think that
现在 如果你想
with that responsibility if you can do something else you should do.
肩负着那个责任 如果你也能做些事你应该去做
But the main thing is that,
但是主要的事请是
and if you don't do that, is to look after your children, to give them joy,
如果你们不去做这些的话　照看你们的孩子　给他们快乐
have a beautiful nest for them,
给他们一个美丽的小窝
then I must say that you are neglecting your basic duty
然后我必须要说你们在忽视你的责任
and your attention is on something else.
你们的注意图放到别的事情上了
That's why so many divorces are taking place and problems are there,
那就是为什么会有这么多的离婚和问题出现
the women ask for their rights, they go beyond their limits,
妇女要求得到权力　她们却超出了权力之外
they became dominating here, the men become dominating.
她们变得爱管制　男人们也要管制
That's not the way we are going to solve it.
那不是我们解决问题的办法
We have to know that we are two wheels,
我们要知道夫妻是两个轮子
two wheels of one chariot,
一辆战车上的两个轮子
one on the left, another in the right.
一个在左　一个在右
Now they are not similar,
它们是不一样的
they're not similar they are two types one left side one right side.
它们不一样因为一个在左边一个在右边
But, they are equal.
但是　它们是平等的
In their, whatever they do it's equal,
无论它们做什么都是平等的
they are to be respected equally in the same manner.
它们同样的要平等地被尊重
And it is always so for example,
一直都是这样的　举个例子
I had a girl who came to me
有个女孩来找我
and she was a private secretary,
她是一个私人秘书
and she told me: 'Mother you say this,
她告诉我说　母亲您是这样说
but I've seen that all these men come and flirt with their private secretaries.'
但是我看到的是所有那些男人和他们的私人秘书调情
So I said: 'All right, maybe so, but what does that matter.'
我说：好吧 也许是这样 但是这有什么关系
You see that shows that's something wrong with the man, he
这表明这个男人有些问题
doesn't understand, he's off his head, he
他不明白 他昏了头
cannot enjoy his wife and he's running after other things.
他不能享受他的妻子而追逐其他事物
It's like having something in your house and you are
就像你的家里有些问题
looking at other things you see.
所以你看着其他的东西
Like in India if you go to some,
像在印度
somebody comes to your house be careful about your things,
有人来你家 你要小心你的东西
but in England I tell them, if somebody comes to your house
但是在英国 我告诉他们 如果有人来你家
be careful about your wife, see.
要小心你的妻子
Is just a little difference between,
这就是两者之间的差别
but the second one is a dangerous thing because fundamental,
后者是危险的
the wife is the fundamental thing,
因为妻子是基本的
because you do not know what she will do, how she will react
因为你不知道她会做什么 她会如何反应
and you do not know how the guests because that is regarded as their freedom.
你也不知道客人会怎么做 因为这是他们的自由a
But if you take away something from somebody's house that's not freedom,
但是你从别人的家里拿走东西 那不是自由
because we can take away anything from somebody's house
因为如果我们能拿别人家里的任何东西
why should anybody arrest us?
那为什么要逮捕我们？
Because there is a free will for you to do what you like,
因为如果有你可以做喜欢的事情的自由
is allowed to do what you like, but in that free will
允许做你喜欢的事情 但是在那样的自由中
you are harming so many people and ultimately your society.
你会伤害许多人 最终是你的社会
Now these two wheels, as I said,
这两个车轮
are very important to God,
对上帝来说非常重要
because so many great people want to take birth on this earth.
因为如此多伟大的人像在这个地球出生
So many great souls want to take birth on this earth,
如此多伟大的灵想在这个地球出生
and if we behave in such a manner,
如果我们以这样的态度行事
that all the time this chariot is this way going up and that way going up,
就像车轮 不时翘起一只轮子
I can tell you no child would be willing
我可以告诉你那些伟大的人每人愿意
to be born in this place who are great people.
在这个地方出生
Only the people who are of the worst type will be born,
只有最坏类型的孩子愿意
they'll be hooligans, they'll be horrible people with a horrid nature
他们将成为街头小流氓 他们将是恐怖的人，有着可怕的习性
and they'll spoil the whole atmosphere of the countries
他们将会扰乱国家的整个氛围
where husband wife have, do not have good relationship.
在此 丈夫和妻子没有好的关系
The children will be such hooligans
孩子也会成为同样的街头流氓
and such horrible things
和这样恐怖的事情
that you'll be surprised that at the age of eight years and five years
你会惊讶的看到8岁5岁年龄的孩子
they'll be committing murders and doing
他们谋杀别人
all kinds of such thing that you'll be shocked.
做各种各样令你震惊的事情
Now between you and me,
现在 你和我之间
because you are also husbands and wife and,
因为我们是丈夫 妻子
one thing it should be there that
需要注意
we should not quarrel before our children.
我们不应当着孩子的面吵架
We should have all decency of husband and wife, there are so many things
我们应该是互相尊重的夫妻 有很多事情
we do not do in the presence of our children.
不能当着孩子的面做
In the same way we need not sit down and
同样我们不需要坐下
quarrel and say: 'I hate you and I hate you'.
吵架 说 我恨你 我恨你
I tell you this is something you have to change little bit in our language.
我告诉你们  在我们的语言中你们需要稍微做一些改变
In India if somebody says: 'I hate you'
在印度 如果有人说 我恨你
it's regarded, that man regarded as a most unmannerly person.
那么这个人被视为是一个极其粗鲁的人
I mean its very bad manners to say 'I hate you' how,
我是说　对别人说　我讨厌你　是很不好的一种行为
I mean it shows that you are very low type of person to say like that.
那样说话的话　说明你是一种很低级的人
But 'I hate you' so what.
说了　我讨厌你　又能怎样
If you hate so what, you are not God.
如果你讨厌能怎么呢　你又不是上帝
If you hate me what does it matter, actually,
如果你讨厌我　有什么紧要吗　事实上
if somebody hates someone, so what.
如果有人讨厌某人　说明
That shows that person is not a good person, just to hate someone.
这个人不是一个好了　他就会去讨厌别人
'I hate you' is a way of expressing something
我讨厌你　这是在表达某种情绪
that is I feel, is very wrong for the family system. It shocks children.
我感觉这对家庭系统来说是个很错误的表达方式　它会惊吓到孩子
Children look upon you as ideals.
孩子们都把你们当作崇拜者看待.
When they are born you should see them,
当他们出生时你应当照看他们
most of the children nowadays in Australia are born realized,
如今大部分在澳大利亚出生的孩子是天生自觉的
I see them around when I went to the airport and I see they're born realized.
当我到达机场我看到他们 我能看出他们是天生自觉的
And they watch you, and they're surprised
当他们看你 他们是很惊讶的。
and they sulk and they feel very sad.
而且他们不开心 他们感到非常悲伤。
They don't like, they don't take sides,
他们不喜欢站在某一边
they don't like the father to fight the mother, the mother to fight.
他们不喜欢父亲和母亲吵架 母亲也和父亲吵架
And one other thing which you must understand,
你必须要明白另一个事情是
that a certain gradation has to be there.
要有一些等级观念
A woman is the strongest point of the household.
妇女是家中最为重要的
Like this Mother Earth is.
就像大地母亲
She takes all the problems upon Herself.
她自己承受了所有的问题
She, because She's the strongest.
因为她是最坚强的
Who else can withstand this kind of, weight on Her.
还有谁能承担如此大的压力
It's the Mother only can do that.
只能大地母亲才能做到
In the same way a woman in the house is the mother,
同样的一个女人在家里就是母亲
and she has to bear.
她必须去承受
You see it's nice to have a husband
你看她多好 有一个丈夫
who comes home and says whatever he likes
他回家了说些他想说的
and takes out all the filth on you,
去除你所有的不洁
than to have a husband who is very sweet, hello, hello
然后有一个很甜蜜的好丈夫
and outside he goes like a bumptious tiger on everyone.
在外面时他对别人就像一个傲慢的老虎一样
Such a man is, has to be, he has to, you see they're like children I would say,
这样的男人 你看 我可以说他们就像孩子
they are like children. They have to take out their tensions on their wives only,
他们像孩子 他们只对他们的妻子打开心扉
and you should be an absorber of that
你们应该做一个接收者
and that's the sign of a woman.
那就是作为一个女人的标志
A strong woman doesn't get easily disturbed by these things.
一个坚强的女人不会轻易对这些事情干扰
She's not bothered. She says all right,
她不会被打扰 她说 好
you little baby come along,
你这个宝贝一起来
now I have had four babies, now this is the fifth one
我有四个宝贝了 现在这是第五个
which is the smallest has come.
这是最小的一个来了
Let him shout and scream, even with the children,
让他叫喊 即使只是孩子
you have to be patient, they'll hit you, they'll do anything.
你必须有耐心 他们会打你 他们可能会做任何事情
I would say that way in India, children are treated
在印度 人们对待孩子的方式
very kindly and they are special things.
是非常友善的 孩子们是特殊的事物
They will do what they like when they are children,
当他们是小孩的时候 他们会做任何他们喜欢的事情
but when they grow up we do not have teenage problem,
但是当他们长大的时候 我们却没有青少年问题
we do not have problem where the children don't respect.
在小孩被尊重的地方 我们没有相应的问题
In that, this is very important
因为
aspect of our modern life
我们现代生活很重要的一个方面
that we have to understand, what is the relationship of husband and wife is.
就是我们必须去理解 丈夫和妻子之间的关系应该是什么样的
Husband is like say, a gentleman who
丈夫应该像绅士
is definitely is to be respected by the wife.
他受到妻子绝对的尊重
But if she does not respect the husband she cannot
但是如果妻子不尊重丈夫
get respect from her children.
妻子也不能从孩子那获取尊重
But the husband has to be respectable man,
然而丈夫必须是一个值得受人尊敬的人
that's very important. If the man is not respectable, he
这是非常重要的 如果一个男人不值得让人尊敬
cannot be respected easily.
他就不能很容易获得尊重
But the more is the woman has to be very respectable,
但是更加重要的是 女性必须是值得受他人尊敬的
if she doesn't give her respect,
如果她不给与她的尊重
you can handle any kind of man
你可以应付各种类型的男人
if you are clever enough, drunkards, all sorts, they come round.
如果你足够聪明的话 酒鬼 所有类型 他们到来
Because after all they're human beings, they're not bad people.
因为他们毕竟是人类 他们不是坏人
But because of mishandling they just get out
但是因为被粗鲁地对待 他们只好离开
and the domination of men is just a myth.
男性的统治只是一个神话
See, they cannot dominate,
你看 他们不能统治
they're incapable of domination. They just do it because they want to
他们不擅长统治 他们做这些是因为他们想
feel that they are superior, that's all.
觉得他们是高人一等的 就是这样
But they cannot dominate. Whatever domination, what is their domination,
但是他们不能统治 无论是哪种类型的统治 无论在哪里 他们统治的
is little little things here and there.
都是非常微小的事情
Just like children, that's what it is.
就像小孩们 就是这样的
If women understand their maturity and their,
如果女人明白她们的成熟和她们的
their responsibility as women, because they are the shakti,
她们作为女人的责任 因为她们是夏克提女神
they are the power of the family,
她们是一人家里的中间力量
and they are the potent shakti for the husband as well as for the children,
对于丈夫和孩子来说 她们是至高无上的夏克提女神
but if they get disturbed
但是如果她们被干扰了
then the husband is disturbed and children are also disturbed.
然后会使丈夫和孩子都受到干扰
But they are potent, while the kinetics are these people.
但是她们是至高无上的 是这些人的动力所在
Like here is the electricity, all right,
就像这里的电源
so we say very good, lamp and electricity and all that,
所以我们说很好 这些照明灯和电源等等
but from where does it come. The source is somewhere
但是这是从哪里来的 这个来源是从某个地方
quietly sending the source,
默默地传送过来的能源
and enjoying itself by giving that source.
而且把传送能源当成是愉快的事
In the same way this is a very important centre.
同样这是一个非常重要的中心
Why I said it because today I went,
为什么我这样说  因为我今天去
went to Melbourne and all the time this finger was burning up to this point.
去了墨尔本 感觉到了从这个手指到这个中心一直在发热
So that means there's something wrong with
这说明有点问题
men and women as far as their family life is concerned.
关系到男人和女人以及他们的家庭生活
They're all very upset I felt.
我感觉他们都很消沉
The husband is upset and the women.
丈夫很消沉 妻子也是.
Maybe the laws maybe against men, maybe here
可能是这里的法律都是反对男人们的
I don't know. But in America I found
我不知道是不是 但是在美国的时我发现
a husband and wife relationship is very queer.
他们那丈夫和妻子的关系非常奇怪
For example I met a lady, very queer people they are.
比如我见过一位女士 就是个非常奇怪的人
I went and stayed with a lady she had a luxurious house
我去了这位女士豪华的家里
with a swimming pool and this and that,
有游泳池 还有这个和那个
a maid in coming to do everything up and five storeys and this,
有仆人来为她打理五层的楼房
and she said: 'You see my, one of my former husbands
她对我说 您看 我前夫中的一个
will come and see you in Los Angeles.' I said: 'All right very good idea'.
要从洛杉矶来看您 我说 好啊 不错的主意
So he came, he was like a pauper you know walking like this,
所以他来了 你们知道吗他看起来像个乞丐 走起路来是这样的
and he says: 'I have got a room on rents where I'm staying Mother,
然后他说 我把和我母亲住的房子出租了
it's very difficult, I have to share it with someone'. I said: 'What?
生活很困难 我不得不拿它出来合租
That lady who was there,
那位女士就在那儿
she has a very big house, she's supposed to be your wife'.
她有一个很大的房子 她是你的妻子
He said: 'That's mine, I tell you, I lost it to her in a case'.
他说 我告诉你 那房子是我的 我因为一个案子输给她了
I said: 'How could you lose that in a case?'
我说 你是怎么输的
'Because she asked for a divorce and because
因为她要求离婚因为
she found guilty out of me something some,
她在一些事情上认定我是有罪的
so she got it'. And she married three husbands, all the three husbands
所以她就得到了房子 而且她嫁了3个丈夫 这3个丈夫
are moving like paupers, and this lady's very rich.
搬走时都像乞丐一样 这个女士就变得很富有了.
If you marry seven husbands, seven husbands are finished forever
如果你嫁给七个丈夫 七个丈夫会永远毁掉了
but the lady is so rich, seven times more than any one of them.
但是这个妇女很有钱 拥有七倍多于他们其中的任何一个
So this is kind of a law I don't understand.
这是一种我不能理解的法律
First of all why there should be a law, I don't understand,
首先为什么那儿需要有法律 我不理解
between husband and wife.
在丈夫和妻子中
I just don't understand. I mean we don't have such laws in India but
我只是不理解 我的意思是我们在印度没有这样的法律
everybody cares for the wife,
但是每个人都很关心他们的妻子
because she is the nearest and the dearest person they have.
因为她是他们最近和最亲爱的人
Who else to depend? If the woman is dedicated and devoted to husband,
还有谁可以依赖 如果这个妇女对丈夫专一并且忠诚
do you think he'll run after any other woman, he has to come back to her.
你觉得他会和其他女人跑吗 他会回到她身边
You see he'll be so fed up with these
你明白他会厌恶这些
women who just live for money or anything
为了金钱或者其他东西而生活的妇女
and he has to come back.
他不得不回来
So you see one has to take a very wise decision,
因此你明白必须要采取个明智的决定
because you must understand you are born at a juncture,
因为你必须明白你出生在一个时刻
whether in, on which you will be destroyed completely,
无论在否 你会被完全的摧毁
or you'll be saved completely. Is a very important thing.
或者你将被完全的拯救 这是一件很重要的事情
You have to save humanity. You are born
你需要拯救人类 你出生在
at a time when you have to save humanity.
这样一个你需要拯救人类的时代
It's not only kundalini awakening
它不只是昆达里里的升起
that will help, because you might be saved,
会帮助你们 因为你们也许能得救
but you have to save the whole society,
但你们必须去拯救整个社会
the whole family, the whole,
整个家庭 全部
I should say the whole universe or the whole
我想整个宇宙或者整个
creation will have no meaning if you people are destroyed.
创造将不会有意义一旦你们被破坏
Now you, this is one of the way of destruction,
这就是其中一种破坏
by destroying the family. The children become mad,
家庭的破坏 使得孩子变得疯狂
the husband becomes mad,
丈夫变得疯狂
they all end up in orphanages, that's what I've seen,
他们将在孤儿院度过余生 这是我亲眼所见的
they are mostly in orphanages in their old age,
他们大多数年老时都在孤儿院
there's nobody to bother about you.
再不被人过问
So it's a question of giving, and giving and giving.
So it's a question of giving, and giving and giving. 所以这是一个不断给予的问题
Now this Gruhalaxshmi's centre is on the left-hand side,
Gruhalaxshmi原理作用于左边
and the another is Raja Laxshmi centre is on the right-hand side.
另一个则是作用于右边的Raja Laxshmi
Now this center gives us the power to rule over people
这个能量中心给予我们统领他人的能力
and we become very, in extremes you see we can become very arrogant
而我们却走向极端 我们可以变得十分傲慢
and we can become very very, sort of authoritative and we might,
我们可以变得十分 可以说十分有权势 我们可以
sort of end up with a funeral with ten thousand people behind us,
拥有一个有一万人来追悼的葬礼
all bought from market and put there behind you without any feelings,
这些从市场雇来的人假哭丧
that's all finished. With such a man finished they'll say, oh thank God he died,
一切都结束了 对于这样的人他们会说 哦 感谢神他终于死了
he was a horrible terror for us.
他对我们来说是个可怕的恐怖分子
So, that kind of a life can come with Raja Laxshmi.
所以那是和RAJA LAXSHMI一起的生活方式
But in the center is the Laxshmi.
但在这个轮中心是LAXSHMI
Laxshmi is the Goddess, is the power within us, by which we balance,
LAXSHMI是女神 是我们内在的力量 通过它使我们获得平衡
lead a very balanced life,
过来一种很平衡的生活
by which we are satisfied.
可以使我们感到满足
Now they have made a beautiful picture of this Laxshmi also one
现在他们画了一幅美丽的LAXSHMI画 而且
should understand this power is a Lady,
我们应该明白这力量是一位女士
is a Mother and She stands on a lotus. Now these are all symbols
是一位母亲站在一朵莲花上 这些都是象征
which suggest that,
它说明了
these symbols are carved out with such deep significance.
这些象征被创造出来有很深的意义
She stands on a lotus. Means imagine, who can stand on a lotus?
她站在一朵莲花上 想想是什么意思呢  谁能够站在莲花上呢
And She's a very healthy woman, very healthy woman and She stands on a lotus.
而且她是一个很健康的女人 很健康的女人站在一朵莲花上
It means that, that She is never putting pressure on anyone.
这意思是 她从来不会失压力给任何人
A rich man comes in, he must honk his car,
一个富有的人 他必须按他的汽车喇叭
loudly, because he's rich so he thinks he must honk it higher,
很大的声音 因为他富有然后他认为他必须按喇叭大点声音
and a rich man must go in a big limousine or some sort of
而且一个富有必须坐豪华大车 或者 其他的
a thing to show off that he's very rich.
可以让他炫耀他很有钱的东西
If he comes to any program, or any he must sit in front,
如果他去参加什么活动 他必须要坐在前面
he should have the front seat,
他应该得到前排的座位
and he makes him known everywhere everybody must feel
他必须在每个地方都是被人所知的
the weight of the rich man. He can run away with ten wives,
每个人都要感觉到这个富人的份量 他能与别人的10个妻子私奔
of somebody and, he can have a big
他可以有一艘大船
boat for himself, and he can get any number of women there
他可以得到任何数量的女人
and he can spoil any families he likes because he's rich.
他可以破坏任何家庭 他喜欢这样因为他是富人
This kind of thing comes in in people but Laxshmi the One who has,
这类事情在人类身上出现 但是Laxshmi是那个
stands on the lotus,
站在莲花之上的
is the beauty and the glory of the riches,
她是上帝给予那人的
that God has given that person.
财富的美丽和荣耀
Then, it has got two red, pink flowers in the hand, that are
她手上持有两朵红色 粉色的花朵
lotus flowers again. Now the lotus is regarded as a very
它们也是莲花 在印度 莲花被认为是非常
holy flower in India, because it is so receptive
神圣的花朵 因为它是如此容易被
to everything that is crude and funny. First of all
天然的有趣的事物所接受 首先
it is born in the mud. Just think of it,
莲花生于淤泥之中 只是想象一下
in the mud, in the filth, where the horrible smell is coming out,
在淤泥之中 在污秽之中 那里有非常难闻的气味出来
the lotus is born.
然而莲花盛开
And the one lotus gives the fragrance, the beautiful fragrance
她向整个周围散发着芬芳
to the whole atmosphere,
美丽的香味
and kills all that's filth and everything,
去除了所有的污秽
and covers the whole pond with its big big leaves
她大大的叶子覆盖整个池塘
so that it looks a beautiful pond.
把池塘装扮得非常漂亮
That's what is the lotus for. But this lotus
这就是莲花
is a pink lotus, means pink, you know is the sign of love.
但是这个莲花是粉色的 粉色的 你们知道 粉色象征着爱
Pink is the sign of love. So such a person has to have
粉色是爱的符号 所以一个人必须有
tremendous love and that softness of the lotus.
巨大的爱和莲花般的柔软
Now the inside of the lotus is very soft and nice
莲花的内部非常的柔软和美好
and a, I don't know what do you call that, the bee, the black bee,
然后一个 我不知道你们叫它什么 蜜蜂 黑色种蜜蜂
a very big one which has got horrible,
非常大的一只 它是很可怕的
no, the black bee, it's like that, which has got
不 那个黑色种蜜蜂 它长得象
angular legs and things like that, horrible, you cannot touch it.
它有非常尖的长腿 长相很可怕 你不能碰它
That one, can find its place in the lotus.
那一个 可以在莲花中找到它的位置
When it goes to the lotus, the lotus opens its petals and takes it inside
当它飞向莲花中时 莲花打开了它的花瓣把它包裹在其中
and makes it, sleep on the corona that it has, very soft
然后让它 在冠中休憩 非常柔软
one on the bed, and covers it nicely
的一个在床上 恰好的覆盖着它
and gives it a nice, you see,
给它一个很好的 你是知道的
swinging feeling, that it feels it is in the lap of the mother
一种摇摆的感觉 就像在母亲的膝盖上
and it sleeps off. Even such a animal, it gives a place to live.
睡觉 甚至这样一个动物 它给予了居住的地方
Now the man who is a laxshmipati the one who is blessed with Laxshmi,
现在一个laxshmipati的人 一个享有Laxshmi的人
has to have a temperament like that.
需要有一个像那样的性情
Anybody who comes to his house,
任何去他家的人
anyone, should be very readily accepted. I've seen people like that,
任何人 应该很容易接受 我看到了许多像那样的人
I've seen in my lifetime, should be accepted and they should be
在我的一生中我看到的 应该接受 他们应该
very gratified to have such people in the house
非常的高兴有这些人在家里
and should feel that oh God,
应该觉得 哦上帝
what a blessing it is that we have a guest in the house.
我们有个客人在家里是多大的祝福啊
But in modern times, we find out devices and methods,
但是在现代 我们找出了设备和方法
how to avoid guests,
怎样躲避客人
guests are equal to pests.
客人相当于害虫
I was in London, we were living on Surrey Hills and
我过去在伦敦的时候 我们住在萨利山上
we had bungalows, separate bungalows,
我们有小房子 分开的小房子
quite good bungalows I should say, there were seven bungalows.
非常好的平房 那儿有七间平房
And poor husbands were taken to tasks
可怜的丈夫们被带去修剪草坪
for mowing the lawns and everything and the wife used to
以及其他妻子们通常告诉他们要做的事情
tell them now come along do it properly
他们一起把事情做得很好
and the polishing of the,
擦亮铜器
brass whatever was there and everything was done very well.
以及其他的事情 每件事情都被完成得非常好
But I didn't see even a rat enter those houses,
我甚至没有看见一只老鼠进入这些房间
even a rat, I mean leave alone human beings.
一只老鼠都没有 我的意思是除了人类
Nothing entered those houses, only these two persons used to come out
没有其他的东西进入这些房间 只有这两个人
and go in.
在进进出出
And I don't know they might be having some yearly,
我不知道 他们可能每年都会有一些
some sort of a get-together, maybe.
类似于某种形式的聚会
But nobody, while My house was naturally, I am like this,
但是没有人 而我的房子是自然的 我喜欢这样
so it was open all the time, people would come in and go out and this and that
所以它一直开着 人们可以进进出出
and I was just enjoying their company.
而且我非常享受他们的陪伴
And one day they asked me,
有一天他们问我
what's the matter in Your house, all the time people are
你的房子发生了什么事 所有来来往往的人
coming and going and used to wonder what is it going on inside.
都常常惊讶里面到底发生了什么事情
I said nothing, just they come, have tea and go, that's all, just
我说没有任何事情发生 只是他们来这里 喝杯茶 然后走了 就是这样
some talk together, some rapport of love.
就是在一起谈谈话 享受爱与亲密
But what is this, all the doors are closed,
但这是什么 所有的门都是关着的
that way I must say Sydney people are very open hearted,
我必须说悉尼的人们都是有着非常开放的心的
and they are, they like to be together, there is a togetherness in them.
他们喜欢在一起 他们喜欢欢聚
But with all this, if you cannot have togetherness,
但是这一切 如果你没有与其他人共享
to enjoy your wealth with others,
与他人分享你的财富
then what's the use of all the wealth.
那么财富有什么用处
If you have wealth, you'll go for horse-racing,
如果你富有 你会去赛马
that's also your own enjoyment.
这是你在独自享乐
If you have wealth you will do something else which is so individualistic.
如果你拥有财富 你会做一些非常个人主义的事情
You cannot enjoy your wealth
除非你学会分享你的财富
unless and until you share it.
否则你不能享受它
As I told you the other day that
就像有一天我曾经告诉你们的
I am, a capitalist in the sense I have all the powers within myself.
我内在拥有所有的力量 在这个意义上我是一个资本家
But, I cannot live without sharing it,
但是 我的生活不能没有分享
so I am the greatest communist, because I just cannot enjoy,
所以我是最伟大的共产主义者 因为我不能享受不与人分享事物
that's why I had to come all the way to Australia
这就是为什么我不得不千里迢迢来到澳大利亚
and today my husband was so insistent that I should come back soon,
今天我丈夫坚持我要赶快回来
I said: 'No, I have to meet all the Australians still, and then I'll come.'
我说 不 我要会见所有的澳大利亚人 然后我才回来
So unless and until you share this love after realization,
所以在你得到自觉后 除非你开始分享这爱
you do not enjoy. All isms drop out,
否则你不能享受 所有的主义都在退出
because you become combination of both extremes,
因为你变成两个极端的结合
and you just start enjoying yourself.
你就开始享受你自己
Now this lotus is in the hand
现在莲花在手上
and another hand that the Goddess has is like this. She has four hands,
女神的另外一只手是像这样的 她有四只手
and one hand like this.
一只手是像这样
Now this hand that is like this means,
这只手像这样是说
you see with this we must give, we must give, we must be generous.
你看 我们必须给予 我们必须给予 我们必须是慷慨的
Miserly people cannot be the blessed ones,
吝啬的人不可能会是得到祝福的那个
they cannot be. Miserly rich is the horridest thing that you could think of.
他们不能 吝啬的富有是你能够想象到的最坏的事情
Mean, if you see a miserly person,
意思是说 如果你看一个吝啬的人
I mean, I don't know, I get a headache with a man like that, you see, who
我的意思是 我不知道 我被一个这样的人弄得很头疼 你看
goes on counting each and every pi
他对每件事都打算盘
and measuring everything, you see miserly horrible things
算计每件事情 你看吝啬这样糟糕的事情
and ultimately when they die, their children
最终的结果就是当他们死了 他们的孩子
take out all their money and just spend it over.
拿出他们所有的钱 挥霍一空
They have, miserly people have another way of
他们有 那些吝啬的人们有另外一种
getting their money looted. For example
让他们的钱财洗劫一空的方式 举个例子
a thief might come in, if not thief then,
一个小偷可能进来 如果不是小偷
their children will become very wayward
他们的孩子会变得非常任性
or something will happen,
或一些事情会发生
they will get sick and they'll have hand brokens and
他们会生病 他们会把手摔坏
feet broken or something, and they will have to spend money.
把脚摔坏或其他的事情 然后他们就不得不花钱
So the miserly people are such a nuisance to the society.
因此吝啬的人对社会而言是个麻烦
They give nothing to the society they are
他们没有给予社会任何东西
there for themselves and they are just malignant personalities.
他们只是为他们自己 他们有着非常有害的个性
The people who give,
那些给予的人
not of course I don't believe into giving
当然我不认为应该无节制地
into somebody freely because that also can spoil people.
给予 因为这样也会将人们宠坏
If you give something to someone very freely,
如果你无节制地给一些人东西
they can be completely spoilt and,
他们会完全地被宠坏
they would not know how to use that money.
他们不知道如何用那钱
This is the trouble with human beings is,
这就是人类存在的问题
that they cannot bear anything.
就是他们不能承受任何东西
If you give them money,
如果你给他们钱
either they'll become miserly or they become wayward.
他们要么变得非常吝啬 要么变得非常任性而为
If you give them power either they become dictatorial
如果你给予他们权力 他们要么变得非常独裁
or they become destroyers.
要么变成破坏者
I mean, you cannot give anything to human beings
我的意思是 没有自觉
without realization.
你不能给予人类任何东西
Anything they get extreme, they become mad.
任何东西他们都会变得极端 变得疯狂
That's one word you can explain.
那是用一个词你就可以解释的
Now Krishna has said, 'yoga kshema mahatmyam'.
现在克利须那神说过 瑜伽kshema mahatmyam
He has said I give you Yoga,
他说 我给你瑜伽
that is union with God, self-realization,
那是要与神连结 得到自觉
and then I look after your kshema,
然后我来照管你的kshema
and kshema means your well-being.
kshema 意思是你的福祉
This well-being is brought forth with this Laxshmi,
这福祉和这个laxshmi一同产生
with one hand that is giving, the another is the protection.
在一只手是给予 另一只手是保护
This hand which gives, should not, the other hand should not know.
这只给予的手不用让另一只手知道
It should be so done so gracefully, graciously.
它是如此优雅的仁慈的完成的
Today only I was telling the story to some people,
今天我讲一讲某个人的故事
about my own father,
关于我的父亲
who was a very generous man I've ever known.
他是我所知的一个非常慷慨的人
And he had a habit on a Sunday afternoon he used to go,
他过去在每个周日下午有个习惯
he used to call all the people and say that I have to
他告诉所有人说 我要
give away lots of things, I have too many things in the house.
赠送很多东西 我房子里有太多东西了
He'd take out all the blankets, sometimes all the
他拿出所有的毯子
utensils and sometimes food, anything that he felt like he used to give way.
餐具 有时候是食物 任何他感觉可以赠送的东西
So people would come and he would pass on and his head was bent like that,
所以人们都来 他都分给东西 他一直低着头
and some people told him, what's the use, some people are
有些人告诉他 有什么用呢 一些人是
taking three blankets, some are taking two blankets,
有人拿走3条毯子  有人拿走两条
you don't even see what's happening you are just giving away,
你只顾着给出  发生了什么事你甚至不清楚
please at least raise your head.
请至少抬起头看看
So he said: 'The problem is like this,
我父亲说  问题在于
because I don't give, it's God Who is giving,
因为不是我在给出   是上帝在给出
I'm just standing in between.
我只是站在给予者和收受者之间
And they all are saying that
他们都说
you are giving you are giving, thank you, thank you.
谢谢你的给予  谢谢
So I feel very shy, first of all.
所以我一开始还感到有点害羞
And secondly it is the lookout of God who is giving these things
但又想到这是上帝在给予这些物品
to see whether one gets two or one. Why should I bother.
由他照管谁拿了两个或一个  我就不必为此烦恼了
I'm just standing in between, I'm not supposed to see who takes two or one.'
我只是站在两者之间  我不想看到谁拿了两个或一个
Such generosity I've seen, in my own lifetime.
在我自身的生命里  总是看到这样的事发生
And I have seen, the more generous he was,
我也看到  他越慷慨地付出
the more generosity flew into our house.
财物就越多地流入我家
I mean, that like if you open this door from the other side it starts flowing.
我的意思是  就像你打开门的另一面  财物开始流动起来
But some people have sixty shirts, but still they'll go
但有些人已有60件衬衣了  他们仍然
to the market and buy shirts.
去市场上买更多的衬衣
And they'll say: 'Oh I have a weakness for shirts.'
而他们会说  噢  我急缺衬衣
Now I don't understand this weakness
现在我弄不懂这种缺乏
of heaping up shirts after shirts.
家里的衬衣都成堆了
It is ridiculous, isn't it.
很荒唐 不是吗
Some of these things really are ridiculous,
这些事情真的是很荒唐
that I have a weakness for shoes,
有人说我急缺鞋子
now you go and see the shoes are from top to bottom,
你去看 他家的鞋子从上到下堆满了
you can open a shoe shop, or,
你可以打开一个鞋柜 或者
it's like that, what's the use of getting so many shoes
诸如此类  买这么多鞋子有什么用呢
because your foot has got the same size for years now,
因为你的脚多年来已是同样的尺码
it's not going to change, even after realization.
不会变了  即使获得自觉之后
So there is no need to, I mean if your shoes give way is all right
所以没有必要再买  我的意思是如果你给出一些就好了
but, I too have the same problem. That
但 我也有同样的问题
I, My disciples know that they should give me a shoe, I don't know why,
不知道为什么 我的一些弟子想要送我一双鞋
they give me a shoe, all the time I go there they give me
他们给我一双鞋  我走哪里都穿他们给的这双鞋
chappal or a shoe or something. I said now
拖鞋或鞋什么的 我说
I've too many now what to do?
我有太多的鞋了 现在我该怎么办
They said: 'Mother return it to us we'll keep it for vibrations.'
他们说 母亲请还给我们 我们会保存 因为有能量
I said: 'That's a good idea,' because I have no place
我说 是个好主意 因为我也没有地方
to keep all these shoes, I mean I am not a cobbler,
保存这些鞋 我又不是鞋匠
I cannot do anything with it.
对此我无能为力
So it is useless.
对我来说它们毫无用处 当要送什么给别人时 他们会送人造的物品
At least don't wear at that time the diamond,
至少那个时候不要戴什么钻石
at least that much decency should be there.
至少这礼物上应该有些许心意
So you see when it comes to giving, give it with your full heart.
所以当你给出礼物时 你应该用全部的心意送出
You just feel that love of giving
你只需感受那种给出的爱的感觉
and you feel so happy, because you feel so big about yourself,
你感到如此快乐 因为你对感到自己高大起来
like an ocean that's giving so much of clouds
就像海洋产生这么多的云朵
and again it is receiving these rivers into it, and again making it into clouds,
大海收纳了这么多的江河 然后又造出云朵
a sort of a circle of beautiful conversion into beauty
形成一个从美丽到变为美丽的循环
after beauty starts, it's so beautiful.
在开始美的创造后 是如此的美丽
And that's what we should try to become,
那就是我们应该达到的
a part of that circle, which is so beautiful
那样一种美丽的循环
and which is so joy giving, to yourself also.
这一切充满了喜乐 对你和那接受的人
And this is what it is, and this hand is for ashraya, means for the protection.
就是这样  这只手用来保护
You must protect the people who are your subordinates,
你必须保护那些跟随认同你的人
who are dependent on you, your children.
他们依靠你 是你的孩子们
Like, it's a very common thing to insult your children from their childhood.
正如 从小你责骂孩子是很普遍的事
Why did you spoil that carpet?
为什么你要弄脏那地毯
Why did you do that? You should not have said this,
为什么你要这样做 你不应该这样说
why did you? This is a very wrong thing of discipline.
你为什么要这样做 这是一个非常错误的训导
Best discipline is to put dignity into children.
好的训导是把尊贵放在孩子里
You see, a good home in India we'll say,
你知道 我们说的在印度一个好的家庭
is known by the way children are addressed in the family.
是通过家庭中的小孩被知晓的
Like, in a good family we address the children like sa.
就像 在一个好的家庭我们叫孩子叫sa
Little bit like that, ap, means sa. We never address the children with indignity,
有点像那个 ap意思是sa 我们从来不用不礼貌的方式称呼孩子
and we put them on a dignified level.
我们把他们放在一个尊贵的水平上
And it's a very nice thing. I'll tell you about my own granddaughter,
这是个非常好的事情 我会告诉你关于我孙女的事情
that, somebody was telling her one day that, there's a very, this boy
有个人一天告诉她 有个很合适的男孩
and why don't you marry him. She said: 'Why do you want to talk about marriage?
你为什么不嫁给他 她说你为什么想要谈论婚姻
I'm not yet grown at all to think about marriage,
我还没成长到可以谈论婚姻的年纪
and we have to be dignified about things,
我们需要尊贵的对待这些事情
how can we think of marriage when we are not to think,
我们怎么能考虑婚姻当我们还不能考虑的时候呢
and my grandmother will marry me and I want to live, a dignified person.'
我的祖母会嫁给我 我想要活着 成为一个尊贵的人
A little girl of seven years said this to this woman who was very,
一个7岁的小女孩对一个妇女说 她是一个属于
sort of pseudo-intellectual type and she tried
伪知识分子类型的人 她试着
to tease my granddaughter. She said: 'It's not dignified'.
取笑我的孙女 她说这不是尊贵
Just think of that. At the age of seven years they have their sense of dignity.
只要想到这一点 在7岁的年纪他们有自己的尊贵的感觉
If you tell them, you see they, you need not tell them don't spoil the carpet,
如果你告诉他们 你可以明白他们 你不需要告诉他们不要糟蹋地毯
but give them dignity they will never spoil it. You'll be surprised.
但是只要给他们尊严的话他就就再也不会损坏毯子了 你们将会很吃惊
Because we all the time cut them short, they become so bad.
因为我们一直都在缩小他们 他们变得很伤心
They want to, they think we are good for nothing, we don't know
他们认为我们什么都不好 我们不知道
what to do, all the time they're telling us like this.
做什么 他们就一直在像这样告诉我们
Or even if you have to tell them, tell about somebody else,
或者甚至你要去告诉他们 关于其他人的事
like that boy, you know, he was absolutely
就像那个男孩子 你看 他是完全
useless, he didn't know what to do,
没用了 他不知道要做什么
he spoiled the whole carpet, I went to his house and slipped down.
他破坏了整块地毯 我去他家里时滑倒了
The child immediately gets the thing.
孩子都很会学样
But directly all the time hitting the child,
但是直接就一直地打孩子
you see gives him a personality
你看 给了他一个性格
which does not hold,
但是承受不了
anything substantial within.
任何本质的东西
He might later on became a very arrogant person taking a cue from his parents,
他以后可能像他的父母一样变成一个很自大的人
and he may behave the same manner,
他的行为也会和他父母一样
but he would not be that dignity
但是他不是那种的高贵
which just is silent and is expressing and manifesting.
而是用沉默来表达
It should be a silent dignity which just manifests,
它应该是用沉默表达的一种高贵
and when people see such a person,
每当人们看到这种人的时候
it happens, people see and say 'Oh what a man, what a dignity'.
就会说 多么尊贵的一个人
You see that's what, and they become sort of ideals for society.
这就是尊严 他们成为这个社会的典范
I think this, correcting the children is not the way,
我想靠纠正孩子的错误不是根本方法
it is not disciplining, but it is making them grow.
不是靠惩罚 而是让他们自然成长
What we have to give to our children is the joy,
我们需要给孩子的是快乐
is happiness of the family, is the complete security,
是幸福的家庭 是完全的保护
a sense of complete security
是绝对的安全感
and you will see you'll never have teenage problems,
这样你会发现你的孩子没有青春期问题
never have teenage problem.
一点青春期问题也没有
You'll be surprised you put them anywhere,
你会惊讶地发现无论你带他们去哪儿
they'll be so dignified and so mature, that people will be amazed.
他们都表现得如此有尊严 如此成熟 令所有人感到惊讶
You won't have to tell them. Even small little children I've seen,
你无需告诉他们怎么做 我见过就连很小的孩子
if you keep your house very clean,
如果你的房子保持干净
and also always look after it, children themselves will keep it clean.
而且经常打理 孩子们自己就会保持干净
They would like to do. Because children are
他们愿意这么做 因为孩子就像
really the budding beauties.
美丽的花骨朵
When we cut them we cut them at the root.
要从根上嫁接他们
They expect so much from us you see,
他们太依赖我们
they lose all their dignity
就会失去所有的尊严
and I'll tell you try this with your children,
请尝试这样对待你们的孩子
give them dignity, you will be amazed how they behave.
给他们尊严感 你将会惊讶于他们的表现
We say they are spoilt, I've never see
我们说他们被惯坏了
children being spoilt when they are dignified.
我从没见过当小孩子被有尊严地对待时他们会被惯坏
Like my own grandson is a realized soul who's a very great person and
就像我的孙子是一个自觉的灵 他是一个非常棒的人
all his friends are above twenty-five years,
他所有的朋友年龄都在25岁以上
you see he's just a five six year old boy and
你看他还只是一个五六岁的男孩
he doesn't like to wear any dress which has got
他不喜欢穿任何滑稽可笑的衣服
funny faces and all that He says:
并且他说
'This is like a clown, I'm not a clown,
这看起来像个小丑 我不是小丑
I don't want to wear'. I found it very difficult in Singapore to buy
我不想穿它 我发现在新加坡为他买一条
a pant for him
看起来不滑稽可笑的裤子
which didn't have any funny faces,
是非常困难的
because all of them had Mickey Mouse this that.
因为这里所有的裤子都有米老鼠在上面
And I've seen my grandchildren also,
我也看见我的孙女
daughters, there these dolls with, you see this ducky
那儿有一些洋娃娃
what you call the duck sort of a face you see.
有着一张鸭子一样的脸
They said: 'What's wrong with these dolls,
他们说 这些洋娃娃出什么问题了
they should know how to put their lips. This is not good.'
它们应该知道如何放它们的嘴唇 这是不好的
I mean you see, they themselves know, that this is wrong.
我的意思是 你看 他们自己知道 这是错误的
'She's going to go into tantrums.' That's what they say.
她快要发脾气了 这是他们说的
This duck is going to go into tantrums
这只鸭子快要发脾气了
that's why she is behaving like this,
这是为什么她有这样的行为
oh like that, you see they are great-grandmothers sometimes the way they
你看他们做事的方式
do some things and the way they behave.
他们的行为方式 就像他们是伟大的曾祖母
But we must give them
但是我们必须给予他们
real love and joy and happiness,
真正的爱 喜悦和幸福
that's the thing we can give to our children
这是我们能够给予我们孩子的东西
and you'll be amazed that this Australia is going to be blessed with children
你将会惊奇澳大利亚将会得到
who are very great saints,
那些小孩的祝福 这些小孩是伟大的圣人
very very great saints. I know that,
非常非常伟大的圣人 我知道
and you have to look after them with dignity.
你们必须用尊严去照看他们
Very great saints are going to be born in this country,
在这个国家即将出生非常伟大的圣徙
so I have to request to you, that forget your problems,
所以我必须要求你们 忘掉你们所有的问题
husband wife problem, is nothing. Look after your children,
夫妻之间的问题 算不了什么 好好照顾你们的孩子
give them dignity, give them a nest where they could live,
给他们尊严 给他们一个能够好好成长的窝
forget because I've seen in England I've seen
我要你们忘记是因为在英国我看到
even an eighty-year old woman behaves like a bride
一个80岁的妇女却表现得像个新娘
I mean she doesn't get over her feeling that she was a bride.
我是说她还没有从做新娘的角色里恢复过来
Like one of the 'Great Expectations'
就像电影 远大前程 里的一个演员
you must have read of Charles Dickens where there was a bride
你应该读过查尔斯狄更斯的这本小说 里面有个新娘
who was sitting all the time thinking she was a bride.
她天天就想着她是个新娘
I see that picture even today,
我今天都看到了那副画
all the time they are in bridal mood.
他们一直都处在刚刚新婚那种状态下
You see you are a mother and you have to treat your children with that dignity
你要明白 你是个母亲你必须有尊严地对待你的孩子
and with that love that a mother should give.
给他们一个母亲应该给予的爱
It is very difficult for some people
这对有些人来说非常的困难
to accept the position of a mother,
去接受这个当母亲的位置
they think why women should be the mothers.
他们认为为什么女人应该要做母亲
I said this is the greatest things look at me. Look at me.
我说当母亲是最伟大的事业 看我 看我
This is the greatest thing to be the mother,
能当母亲是最伟大的事
to love everyone, that they depend on you for
爱每个人 他们都依靠你
love and guidance, just for love.
你能给予他们爱与引导 正是因为爱
Such a great thing to feel: 'Oh God
这种感知力多么伟大 哦
see how much I can give, how many cups I can fill,'
我能付出多少 我能用爱填满多少杯子
it's such a great feeling,
多么伟大的感知力
I wish you would know what a mother is and the,
我希望你们能明白母亲这个身份代表什么
motherhood you have to learn from your children and grandchildren and expand it
你要把母爱推广到孩子 孩子的孩子
to the whole universe. It's such a great thing a woman has in the same way
到整个宇宙 一个妇女身上的Gruha Lakshmi的特质是如此伟大 同样
the father has to do a lot of things about which I will tell you
父亲也需要做许多事情 关于这个我今后会讲
when we go to the other center.
当我们去另一个中心
I think I've talked at length on this center because
我已经谈论了很多关于这个中心的事情
all the time what I find these two centers are catching
一直以来我发现 在澳大利亚 这两个能量中心
very much in Australia.
是有很多感染的
So we have to talk about the things that are catching on this and this.
所以我们必须谈论这些受感染的事情
And today I saw there five six children with their both the fingers in,
今天我看见有五六个孩子都把手指放在嘴里
all realized children with those fingers they were sucking,
都是获得自觉的孩子 他们吮吸手指
and they were showing me again sucking like that.
他们这样吮吸 一再展示给我看
So you can imagine how much it is,
所以你能想象这个能量中心是多么有问题
and otherwise this one and this means that
这意味着
you have been going to some unauthorized personality.
你去过一些假导师那里
If you are going to some unauthorized personality this thumb will be caught up,
如果你去过一些假导师那 这个拇指就会被感染
that's why children put their things in their mouths and
这是为什么小孩子把他们的手指放在嘴巴里
Freud has his own nonsensical theory,
弗洛伊德有他自己的荒谬理论
but actually it is the center that is catching
但是事实上是这个能量中心有感染
with these born-realized children are showing you.
这些天生自觉的孩子在展示给你看
Now for today, I may not be able to cover other
今天我可能不能讲另外一个能量中心太多
centers so much, but later on,
但是稍后
what is the date we are having the program now?
下个计划的日期是什么时候
Next Monday Wednesday Friday,
下周一周三周五
three days are there out of which I will cover all these centers
三天的时间 我可以讲这些能量中心
and specially that of Christ I would like to speak,
我尤其希望讲耶稣的那个能量中心
because I met some people, when I went to America
因为我遇见一些人 当我到美国的时候
I was telling the people there
我告诉那儿的人们
that you are to be born again,
你将会再次出生
you are to be born again and you must have your realization,
你将会得到重生 你必须得到自觉
so what I found whatever lecture I gave there were big big,
所以我发现在美国无论是我做的任何演讲
much bigger than these you see, they had brought to tape
都比你们所看见的这些要大得多 他们将我的演讲录制下来
all my speeches, and the people who organized my program told me that:
组织这个活动的人告诉我说
'Mother you'd better get it patented or don't allow them to tape it.'
母亲 你最好有专利 或者不让他们录制
I said: 'Why?' They said: 'They will be publishing these are all writers
我说 为什么 他们说 他们将会出版这些录像 这些都是记者
and this I said: 'Very good let them write.'
然后我说 非常好 让他们写吧
But some of them started an organization called 'born again', imagine.
但是他们中的一些人发起了一个叫做 重生 的组织 想象一下
Now if I said you have to be,
现在如果我说你必须得到重生
then you start an organization that we are already self-certificated.
然后你成立一个组织说我们已经自我认证了
You see it's a thing one should understand you are to be born again.
人们应该要明白你将会得到重生的真实含义
Now Christ has said that you will be born through Me. Is a fact.
耶稣基督曾经说过你将会通过我而得到重生 这是事实
Where is Christ, is here. This is the gate, see the narrow gate
耶稣基督在那儿 就是这儿 这是门户 看这个狭窄的门户
and your kundalini has to pass through that.
你的昆达利尼必须要通过它
Now in case it does not pass you have to say Lord's Prayer.
万一灵量没有通过 你必须说主祷文
You have to take the name of Christ
你必须以耶稣基督的名义
and you have to adore Him,
你必须要崇拜他
then only it passes through, shows that you have passed through Christ.
只有当它通过了 才表示你已经通过了耶稣基督
You enter into the kingdom of God which is the,
你进入神的国度
limbic area. So, it's a fact
它是大脑的边缘区 所以
when He said you have to pass through Me
当耶稣基督说你必须通过他 这是事实
He didn't mean that people who are self-certificated
他不是说那些自我认证的人们
can say that: 'All right this is Christ,
可以说 好的这是耶稣基督
this is Bible this is Christ,' as if Christ is somewhere lying there,
这是圣经 这是耶稣基督 就好像耶稣基督躺在那儿一样
you just have to turn a stone and you get Him there.
你只需要转动一块石头 然后你就在那儿找到他了
Christ is here. How do you approach Him is only
你如何找到耶稣
through the kundalini awakening and it passes through Christ.
只有当昆达利尼被唤醒 它通过耶稣基督 你才能接近他
This is the door.
这就是门
Now say, you are all Christians or maybe you are Jews or whatever it is,
比如说 你们都是基督徒或者可能是犹太教或者其他的
but, in India for example
但是 例如在印度
they have a very antagonistic feelings towards Christianity.
他们对基督教有一种非常敌对的情绪
Now even a Hindu, or a Muslim,
现在甚至是对印度教 或者对伊斯兰教
if he denies he says all right I don't believe in Christ. He has to.
如果他否认 他说好吧我不信基督 他必须这样
I have to tell him that: 'See,
我必须告诉他 看
if you don't believe in Christ I cannot give you realization.
如果你不信基督 那我不能给你自觉
You have to ask for forgiveness,
你必须请求原谅
and you have to request Christ, then only this will pass through.
你必须请求基督 只有这样才能通过
Now there may be Jews or Christians,
现在这儿可能有犹太人或基督徒
any type, they have to know that all of them are here.
任何种类 他们需要知道他们所有的人都在这儿
For example there was a doctor who came from,
例如有一个医生他来自
Tehran to see me, he had cancer,
德黑兰来看我 他得了癌症
and he came to see me, he had this cancer of the stomach,
他跑来看我 他得了胃癌
so I told him that: 'Do you believe that Mohammed Sahib was the same
因此我告诉他 你相信默罕默德和
as Dattatreya or Nanaka?' He said: 'No I don't even believe,
Dattatreya和Nanaka一样吗 他说 不 我甚至都不相信
when you say that He was Moses or Abraham.
当你说他是摩西或亚伯拉罕的时候
I said: 'He was Moses Abraham
我说 他是摩西或亚伯拉罕
and they are very powerful personality.
他们都有非常强大的人格
Unless and until you accept,
除非直到你接受
that He was Moses and Abraham,
他就是摩西和亚伯拉罕
you are not going to get it.
否则你不会获得
He said: 'Ah, I cannot say that,' because Jews and Muslims are like this.
他说 啊 我不能这样说 因为犹太人和穆斯林就是这样的
I said they both are the same they are very great personalities,
我说他们一样都具有伟大的人格
you are just fighting for nothing at all.
你只是纠结在无谓的事情上
I know Who is Moses and I know Who is, Abraham.
我知道谁是摩西谁是亚伯拉罕
But he would not accept, for eight days, then his wife, you know
但是他那时没有接受 过了八天 他的妻子
she was wiser, she said you'd better get it, you are not well,
她是个很智慧的人 她说你最好接受它 你现在很不好
you'll die, better get it, then they came.
你将要死掉 最好接受它 然后他们来了
You see this is what happens, they are just compelled.
你看这就是发生的事情 他们只是被强迫的
He came: 'All right Mother what ever you say I will accept.' I said: 'Not that,
他来了说 好的母亲无论你说什么我都接受 我说 不是这样的
from your heart you have to say,' and he was cured,
你应该发自内心的这样说 然后他被治愈了
for your information he was cured.
他被治愈的信息供给你们参考
So do not have any extreme ideas,
因此不要有任何极度的想法
They are all in there, and They are all One.
他们全部在那儿 他们全部是一个整体
Only we are fighting saying this is mine, that is mine,
只有我们开始挣扎着说这是我的 那是我的
so this is I have just hinted that this center because I think
因此这是我刚刚说到的中心因为我觉得
that's a very important center
那是个很重要的中心
as I have discussed with the void, about all these Abraham,
我已经和虚空讨论了关于所有这些亚伯拉罕
Moses and all the Old Testament, which is so important.
摩西和所有旧约全书 他们都是很重要的
How, and how Christ is the One, Who,
怎样 基督是怎样成为一个
stays there, Who crucified Himself, to make a path
他停留在那儿 他自己被钉在了十字架上 为了
for us to pass through, why His crucifixion was necessary.
给我们开出一条可以穿过的路 为什么他的刑罚很重要
So I'll spend more time on that later on. I hope
因此之后我会花更多的时间谈论这个 我希望
you'll make it convenient to come again, and I hope you'll get a better hall,
你们可以方便的时候再来 我希望你们会有个更好的礼堂
they are feeling very warm here. Thank you very much.
这儿他们感觉非常热 非常感谢